ellenmacarthurfoundation.org 2019-06-16

# Ellen MacArthur Foundation Policies

## Editorial Policy

### Content aims and quality criteria

Our aim is to provide the public with accurate, up to date, and freely accessible information, sourced from reputable experts in the fields of energy and resources, design, engineering, education, economics and any other topic relevant to the debate regarding a regenerative and restorative circular economy. These experts have, at all times, the possibility to update, modify and edit the content they provided to the Ellen MacArthur Foundation Editorial Team.

### Opinions

The views expressed on the site by external contributors do not necessarily reflect those of Ellen MacArthur, the Ellen MacArthur Foundation team, or the Ellen MacArthur Foundation partners and their employees.

### Independence

The information provided by the Ellen MacArthur Foundation Editorial Team has no bias with regard to political opinions, commercial or corporate considerations. Editorial content will never be paid for by advertisers, sponsors or agencies.

### Diversity

Our aim is to ensure a fair balance of opinion, in order to present the site users with an impartial view of issues or topics our editorial content focuses on. The Ellen MacArthur Foundation Editorial Team will not deliberately favour one side over the other, should the issue tackled present polarized views and/or diametrically opposed political stances.

### Right to quote – Fair use

The Ellen MacArthur Foundation Editorial Team complies with international laws regarding intellectual property and copyright protection. Excerpts or passages of previously published material will always involve a clear and comprehensive reference to the author, the title of the original publication, the publisher’s name and/or the url of the original document.

## Funding Policy

The Ellen MacArthur Foundation is a UK-registered charity with a mission to accelerate the transition to a circular economy. It aims to provide a vision and framework for this transition in three key areas:

  * Education - inspiring a generation to re-think, re-design and build a positive future
  * Business - catalysing circular innovation across the economy
  * Insight & Analysis - providing thought leadership and robust evidence about the benefits of the transition

Funding for this activity comes from two key areas:

  * the business with whom it works - The majority of the Foundation’s funding currently comes from its Global Partners and Circular Economy 100 members, who both commit to a three-year programme of circular economy activity. The team works to continue to grow the membership of both groups.
  * research or education-oriented trusts and grants - The Foundation seeks trust and grant funding for its work in insight and education. It has received funding from the EU, as well as from private organisations, such as the MAVA Foundation, to deliver specific pieces of research on key topics. This research is key to the Foundation’s ability to validate the benefits of the circular economy and such funding continues to be sought.

Details of the Foundation’s funding status can be found in its Annual Report and Accounts available from Companies House and the Charities Commission in the UK. 

[An abridged version of the Report and Financial Statement for the year ended 31 August 2017 is available here.](https://www.ellenmacarthurfoundation.org/assets/downloads/abridged-accounts-31-august-2017.pdf)  

## Privacy Policy

Ellen MacArthur Foundation ('we', 'us' or 'our') is committed to protecting and respecting the personal data that we hold. This policy explains how we process your personal information which will be either as described in this statement or as made clear before collecting your data. If we make changes to our Privacy Policy that affect how we handle your personal information, this statement will be updated. When collecting and using personal data, our policy is to be transparent about why and how we process personal data.

### Our contact details

Ellen MacArthur Foundation and Ellen MacArthur Foundation Trading Limited  
Sail Loft, 42 Medina Rd, Cowes, Isle of Wight, PO31 7BX, United Kingdom  
T +44 (0) 1983 296463  
Email: privacy@ellenmacarthurfoundation.org

### What information do we collect?

When you register as a user of our site, to receive our emails or to attend one of our events, we will collect the personal information necessary in order to provide those services. Typically, we will ask for your name, job title, email address and the organisation which you work for.

### What do we use your personal information for?

We use your personal information in order to personalise the services we provide to you, and in order to improve your experience of our website. We will send you our newsletter approximately two times a month. We may send extra emails out where something significant happens that we think will be of interest to you, for example where you have subscribed to receive such updates, during one of our events.

### How long do we hold data for?

We keep data for as long as is considered necessary for the purpose(s) for which it was collected or for business, operational or legal purposes.  

### Sharing of personal data

We will only share personal data with others when we are required to do so or when we have your explicit consent. When we share data with others, we put contractual arrangements and security mechanisms in place to protect the data and to comply with our data protection, confidentiality and security standards. Personal data held by us may be shared with contractors who carry out work on our behalf, for example we use third parties to support us in providing our services and to help provide, run and manage our internal IT systems.

### Cookies

Cookies are small text files, stored on your computer, which can be used by websites to make a user’s experience more efficient. We use cookies to help improve your experience of our website – for example by looking at content viewed, and to remember things like your login details and preference settings. We also use Google Analytics, which counts the number of visitors and uses cookies to analyse how people use our site.

Our website may link through to third party websites (including, for example, for the delivery of podcasts) which may also use cookies over which we have no control. We recommend that in such circumstances, you check the relevant third party's privacy policies for information about any cookies which may be used.

You can log into our DIF website using your Facebook or Twitter accounts. If you do so, those applications will use cookies to collect information about your site usage which we do not control. Your profile picture will also be available to us if you use this option.

You can delete the cookies that are already on your computer by searching in your file management software for your “cookie” folder or directory. You can also choose to decline or block cookies from all websites. More information about this can be found at www.AboutCookies.org. If you block or delete our cookies, then you will not be able to access any parts of the site which require you to sign in and your preferences will not be saved.

### Transferring information overseas

We have offices in the UK, sister organisations in America and Brazil and are recognised as an ANBI in the Netherlands. We also hold events in many other countries, and we use a mailing company which is based in America. Your information will be added to our databases, and may be accessed by staff worldwide. Where your personal information is available in other countries, we have taken steps to ensure that the information is appropriately protected.

### Individual's rights

Individuals have certain rights over their personal data and as data controllers we are responsible for fulfilling these rights as follows: 

  * Access to their personal data held by us as a data controller. 
  * Rectification of personal data held by us. 
  * Erasure of their personal data from our systems. 
  * Where we process personal data based on consent, individuals may withdraw their consent at any time by contacting us or clicking on the unsubscribe link in an email received from us. 
  * Other rights to restrict or object to our processing of personal data and the right to data portability. 

If you wish to exercise any of these rights, please send an email to privacy@ellenmacarthurfoundation.org. 

### Complaints

We hope that you won’t ever need to, but if you do want to complain about our use of personal data, please send an email with the details of your complaint to privacy@ellenmacarthurfoundation.org. We will look into and respond to any complaints we receive. You can also write to us at: 

Ellen MacArthur Foundation, Sail Loft, 42 Medina Rd, Cowes, Isle of Wight PO31 7BX, United Kingdom.

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with the UK data protection regulator, the Information Commissioner's Office ('ICO'). For further information on your rights and how to complain to the ICO, please refer to the ICO website <https://ico.org.uk/concerns>. 

This policy was last updated on 9 January 2019.

## Website Terms and Conditions

The Ellen MacArthur Foundation is a registered charity (charity number 1130306) and incorporated as a company limited by guarantee (company number 06897785) with its registered offices at The Sail Loft, 42 Medina Road, Cowes, Isle of Wight, PO31 7BX, with affiliated entities in the UK and US (together “the Ellen MacArthur Foundation”).

### Disclaimer

The content on this website is for general information and interest only. Nothing in these pages constitutes professional advice. While the Ellen MacArthur Foundation tries to keep the information on this website accurate and up to date, it cannot be responsible for any inaccuracies. The Ellen MacArthur Foundation makes no warranties, representations or undertakings about any of the content of this website (including as to accuracy, quality, completeness or fitness for any particular purpose); or any content of any third party website which is referred to or accessed by hypertext link through this website, and shall not be liable to any person for any loss or damage which may arise from the use of any information contained in any of the materials on this website.

The Ellen MacArthur Foundation does not endorse or approve the content of any third party website.

The Ellen MacArthur Foundation reserves the right to change these terms and conditions at any time, and it is your responsibility to check them regularly before using the website. Any changes will be effective as of the date we post them to the site.

### Intellectual Property Notice

Unless otherwise noted, you should assume that the content of these pages, including but not limited to any designs, text, graphics, source code or software belongs to the Ellen MacArthur Foundation. Your access to it does not imply a licence to reproduce and/or distribute the contents of this website without the prior written consent of the Ellen MacArthur Foundation (this does not include content which is expressly made available for you to download).

You may link to any of our pages, provided it is clear to your users that the content is ours. Unless we have expressly agreed in advance in writing, linking must not create the impression that our sites endorses or is affiliated with yours.

The trade marks and logos displayed on the site are the registered and unregistered trade marks of the Ellen MacArthur Foundation. Use of the trade marks and logos is strictly prohibited.

### Accessibility

The Ellen MacArthur Foundation aims to provide a website that is accessible to the widest possible audience. Our website can be viewed on a range of different screen sizes, and the size of text can be changed to suit your needs by using your web browser. We also have a “search” facility to help people find information more easily.

### Governing Law

These terms and conditions shall be construed in accordance with, and governed by, English law and any disputes arising hereunder shall be subject to the exclusive jurisdiction of the courts of England and Wales.
